# **Justin Sicking**

### Lead Game Designer & Software Engineer

201 Emery Road Northglenn, CO 80233 **630-797-1006** Justin.Sicking@gmail.com

### **Summary**

Seasoned Game Designer with nearly a decade of experience over a wide range of design skills including level, systems, usability, monetization and live development/iteration. Loves working in teams and collaborating with others to deliver the best user experience possible. Five years of in depth experience working in Free to Play games with a focus on crafting engaging designs that promote player retention and monetization. Strong desire to push myself and take on new challenges be it design or programming.

# **Experience**

October 2016 - Present

### Sierra Nevada Corporation, Centennial, CO - Software Engineer II

- Development of software training solutions and tools for customers.
- Analyzing and replicating real world hardware/software in simulated training environment.
- Implementation of Software Design ICDs provided by Senior Engineers.
- Successful delivery, installation and training of customer requested mods and updates to simulation environment.

May 2011 - October 2016

### **Backflip Studios, Boulder, CO** - Lead Game Designer

Lead Game Designer - Dragonvale World - iOS/Android

- Designing systems and features such as Dragon Breeding, Events and Social Features.
- Responsible for guiding and providing feedback on the design of game systems and features that members of the design team were tasked with delivering.
- Working with Production team to task out work and responsibilities for members of the design team.
- Working with our usability test analyst to coordinate playtests and then collaborating with the design team to devise plans to iterate upon design based on feedback collected.
- Additionally overseeing in house narrative design and outsourced localization efforts and creation and implementation of definition data required to get content into the game.

#### Lead Game Designer - Dwarven Den - iOS

- Designed and implemented nearly fifty levels of content for final version of game.
- Overseeing and providing feedback on creation of level content by three other members of the design team.
- Analyzing live game retention and monetization numbers and developing design solutions targeted at addressing concerns of such metrics.
- Collaborated in the design of core systems, mechanics, player abilities, gear, perks, and social features.

### Senior Level Designer - Ragdoll Blaster 3 - iOS

- Designed and implemented various levels of content for final version of the game using in house tools.
- Collaborated with other designers on potential monetization strategies for a non Free to Play, level driven game.

#### Game Designer - Boss Battles - iOS

• Came onto project in development as the only designer and was responsible for analyzing and tuning all gameplay content, narrative and improving overall gameplay in order to create a fun, shippable game.

August 2008 - October 2010

#### Robomodo, Chicago, IL - Game Designer

Game Designer - Tony Hawk Ride & Tony Hawk Shred - Xbox 360/PS3/Nintendo Wii

- Responsible for the design and implementation of the "Trick" game mode.
- Design and implementation of level data such as power ups, trick lines, and nav guide paths for casual mode.

January 2007 - August 2008

### High Voltage Software, Hoffman Estates, IL - Game Designer

Game Designer - The Conduit - Nintendo Wii

- Design and implementation of Tutorial, White House and Airport levels of the game.
- Collaborating on the design of weapons, powerups, enemy abilities and narrative of the game.

#### Game Designer - America's Army: True Soldiers - Xbox 360

• Design and implementation of multiple training and mission modes seen in the game.

# **Education**

July 2003 - December 2005

# Full Sail University, Winter Park, FL - Game Design and Development

# **Skills**

C++ Python Keynote/Powerpoint

C# Perforce One-Page Designs

Unity Git Fogbugz

JSON Tortoise SVN Jira

LUA Photoshop